天文台已将“天马”上升为2级风暴
NWS has upgraded the storm Telmar to a category 2.
预计有大雨及风速会达到每小时85公里
Heavy rain and wind speed up to 85 mph are to be expected.
我是沙漠之鹰 仍然没有看见三名失踪的登山者
This is Desert Eagle. Still no visual on the 3 missing hikers.
B对 C队 请与国民警卫队确认是否继续救援行动
Bravo, Charlie, please confirm CIS with rescue ops.
快点
Come on!
LC队 我是救援一队
This is Rescue Team One, Lima Charlie.
我们的警犬不擅长搜索登山者 同时这里变得越来越糟
Our dogs are negative on the hikers, but it's getting worse down here.
- 风暴正在加速 - 沙漠之鹰 现时状况如何?
- Storm is speeding up. - Desert Eagle, what's the status up there?
洪水贯穿大楼 叫你的兄弟们离开这座山 完毕
There is a flood throughout building. Gonna get your guys off the mountain. Over.
所有队伍都移往高地 山洪来了
All teams to higher ground. Big fall of water coming.
营救行动撤消 尽快寻求栖身地
Rescue ops - retreat or seek shelter.
那名骑马的志愿者在哪里?无线电联系不上他
Where's that volunteer on horse back? He's not on radio.
他应该在返回途中 疯了才会下山去
He's gotta be on his way back. He'd be crazy to downhill this.
洪水流窜不定 我们回来前把他叫回
Too much turbulence. We bring it in before we're back here.
- 嘿 嘿 - 嘿 这里
- Hey! Hey! - Hey. Over here!
- 救救我们 - 嘿
- Help us! - Hey!
水流乱窜 洪水快来了
The water is going. There is a lot of water coming.
上来
Get on!
我和妻子一起来的 见过我妻子吗?
I'm here with my wife. Have you seen my wife?
- 快上来 - 你要我们走 她可能就在山下
- Come on. Get on. - You got us go and she could be right down there.
没在那里 我在河下游找到了她 她已死了
She's not. I found her down the river. She's gone.
- 杰米 走吧 - 我要去找她
- Please, Jaime, let's go! - I'm gonna go find her.
杰米
Jaime!
下来吧
Come on down!
去那块大石那边
Get over that round rock!
快点 小伙子
Come on, boy.
靠近点儿 尽量握紧
Get in close. Hold as tight as you can!
我们会死吗?
Are we gonna die?
- 你从哪儿找到他们的呢? - 峡谷两英哩下游处
- So where did you find them? - 2 miles down stream at Base Canyon.
- 确认身份了吗? - 还没 有点难度
- Did you get a positive ID? - Not yet, it's pretty torn up.
嘿 他是谁?
Hey, who is he?
长期志愿服务者 上尉
Volunteers from time to time, captain.
我们人手不足 他可是名追踪高手
Nam burning op, but he's a hell of a tracker.
你还好吗 约翰?
You alright, John?
妻子在第一波洪水中就死了 丈夫跑去找她了
Wife got killed in the first wave, husband ran away.
是的 我们在下游约一英哩处发现了他们
Yeah, we found them about a mile down the river.
你已经尽你所能了 约翰
You did what you could, John.
我们再次感谢您的帮助
And we appreciate your help, again.
嘿 先生
Hey, Mr.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
好小子
Good boy.
- 你累了吗? - 是
- Are you tired? - I am.
你一定冻坏了
You must be freezing.
热咖啡可以帮你暖暖身子
Hot coffee will help you warm up.
我听了新闻报导
I heard the news.
两人死亡
Two people died.
无法救他们
Couldn't save them.
也救不了在战争中的兄弟们
Couldn't save my brothers in the war either.
不要责怪你自己 因为当时你要救另一些人
You cannot blame yourself because you gonna save some people.
你已不在战争中了
You are not in the war anymore.
战争只存在你的脑海里
Only in your head.
但是很难忘掉
It's hard to turn off.
坐在那里 你让我想起了你的父亲
Sitting there, you remind me of your father.
他会坐在外面的摇椅上
He would sit outside, in his rocking chair.
一直冥想 从不说话
Always thinking, never talking.
但你在这有一份不错的工作
But you have done a wonderful job here.
打理这个地方
Running this place.
我很感激你让我留下来
I can't thank you enough for letting me stay.
并帮助加布里艾拉成长
And helping raise Gabriella.
谢谢
Thanks.
晚安 玛丽亚
Good night, Maria.
第一滴血5
最后的血
越战五十周年
国家衷心感激
放松  放松  放松
Easy, easy, easy.
好孩子  来  转弯
Good boy. Come on. Turn.
稳住  孩子  稳住  孩子
Hold, son. Hold, son.
来  孩子  很好
Come on, son. That's it.
转弯  转弯
Turn, turn.
来  来  孩子
Come on. Come on, son.
来
Come on.
-你好  -你好
- Buenos días. - Buenos días.
睡得如何
How did you sleep?
非常好
Pretty good.
我没看到加布里的车
I didn't see Gabri's car.
她打过电话  她很好  约翰
She called. She's fine, John.
她在安东尼娅家
She's at Antonia's.
我还希望她能帮我驯那匹白脸牡马
I was hoping she'd help me ride that new bald-faced stallion.
她会喜欢那匹马的  它很擅长转弯  转弯好手
She'd like that horse. He turns great. Great turner.
是
Yeah.
她会是个好驯马师
You know, she'd be a good trainer.
她擅长和马匹相处
She's got a way with horses.
你不觉得吗
Don't you think?
也许吧
Maybe.
但她要去上大学
But she is going to college.
你以为她想和你一样天天一股马味
You think she wants to smell like horses all the time like you?
那么难闻吗
That bad?
不算难闻  如果你喜欢马的话
No, para nada, if you like horses.
干掉他们
Take 'em down!
不许出错
Make no mistake about it.
我们会赢
We are going to win.
我能向你保证
I can assure you that, militarily,
这策略在军事上无法成功
this strategy will not succeed.
-约翰叔叔  -在这里
- Uncle John! - In here!
下午好
Afternoon.
你伺弄完马了吗
Did you finish working out the horses?
差不多吧
Yeah, pretty much.
你在做什么
What you working on?
你知道这是什么吗
You know what this is?
一把小刀
A small knife.
不  这是大马士革钢
No, it's Damascus steel.
我给你上大学准备的开信刀
It's a letter opener I made for when you go away to college.
再把白色把手嵌上
And I'm gonna add on these white handles.
开信刀
Letter opener?
放你桌子上会很好看的
It'd be beautiful on your desk.
我不想扫你的兴  但现在没人写信了
I hate to break it to you, but nobody writes letters anymore.
那你可以用它赶走男孩子
Well, then you can use it to keep the boys away.
-随便吧  -好
- Anyway. - Okay.
- 推 - 好的 天啦
- Push - Okay, jeez.
- 铰链要加润滑油 - 我可以帮把手
- Have to grease theses hinges. - I can help.
好 昨晚怎么样?
Okay. How did it go last night?
参加派对的人并不多
Well, not that many poople showed up to the party.
- 为什么? - 因为下雨
- Why not? - Because of the rain.
祖母已告诉我 昨晚所发生的事
Grandma told me what happened last night.
关于死去的人
About the people who died.
你还好吗?
You okay?
你知道这不是你的错 对吗?
You know it's not your fault, right?
你尽力了
You tried.
我确实尽力了
I did try.
想去骑马吗?
Do you want to go to ride?
- 去穿上你的靴子 - 好
- Yeah, go puts your boots on. - Okay.
有点疯狂  我要上大学了
It's crazy. I'm about to start college.
我不知道为什么  我不知道我想做什么
I don't know why. I have no idea what I want to do yet.
你像我这么大时知道自己想做什么吗
Did you know what you wanted to do at my age?
知道  我想当兵
Yeah, I wanted to be a soldier.
像我这么大时
At my age?
比你现在还小一点
Even before your age.
你喜欢当兵吗
Did you like it?
我曾有过毕生最好的几个朋友
Well, I had some of the best friends I ever had for a while.
没有你在这里问东问西
It's gonna be real quiet around here
这里会变得特别安静
without you asking all these questions.
-你肯定能扛住  -是啊
- I'm sure you'll survive. - Yeah.
太阳要落山了  我只能再骑一小时了
The sun's setting. I only have about an hour left to ride, okay?
-为什么  -我得去安东尼娅家
- Why is that? - I have to go to Antonia's.
她邀请秋天要去上大学的人
She's throwing this thing for the guys
一起聚会
who are going to college in the fall.
你干嘛不请他们来这里
Why don't you invite them here?
什么
What?
带他们来这里
Bring them over here.
还记得上次他们来吗
Remember what happened last time?
-你把他们吓坏了  -为什么
- You freaked them out. - Why?
因为你一直瞪着他们
Because you wouldn't stop staring at them.
不是
Oh, no.
我有时会那样  但不是故意的
Yeah, I do that sometimes, but it's not intentional.
谢谢邀请  但安东尼娅已经搞定了
Thank you, but Antonia's got it covered.
我们就在这里聚会  行吗
We're just gonna have it there, okay?
带他们看看地道
Show them the tunnels.
什么
What?
带他们看看地道
Show them the tunnels.
你从不让别人进地道
You don't let anybody go in the tunnels.
是的  但他们是你的朋友
No, but they're your friends,
所以他们可以
so they're welcome.
-行  好  -带他们看看地道
- Okay, cool. Yeah. - Yeah, show them the tunnels.
那会很好玩的
Yeah, that would be fun.
我以后肯定会想念和你一起骑马的时光
I'm really gonna miss riding with you.
我也会想念的
I'm gonna miss riding with you too.
准备好
Get ready.
是不是很酷  他从不让别人下来
Isn't this cool? He's never let anyone down here.
真疯狂  兄弟
This is crazy, man.
这音乐真可怕
要是让她妈妈听到...
你喜欢这音乐吗
我能适应
I could get used to it.
我希望她玩得开心
I hope she's having a good time.
你从不让我进地道
You never let me in the tunnels.
你真想进的话  我可以带你转一圈
If you really wanna go in, I'll take you on a guided tour.
不了  谢谢  太脏了
No, thank you. Too dirty.
确实
It is that.
这是个聚会的好地方  宝贝
This is a great place for a party, baby.
现在不行  好吗  我脑子里一堆事
Not right now, okay? I have a lot on my mind.
好  我理解
No, I understand.
-你画的吗  -对
- Did you draw that? - Yeah.
其实是我十岁画的
I drew that, actually, when I was ten years old.
画得真棒
That's a masterpiece.
是谁
Who's that?
我得接这个电话
I got to take this.
吉赛尔
Gizelle?
妹子  你能听见吗  信号不太好
Hey, girl, can you hear me? The reception is not so good.
能  能  我能听见
No, no. Yeah, yeah. I hear you.
都告诉我
Tell me everything.
-加布里埃尔  -怎么
- Gabrielle? - Yeah?
你在这里做什么  你朋友都走了
What are you doing down here? All of your friends have left.
他们搞得乱糟糟的  我在清理
They made a big mess. I'm just cleaning up.
聚会怎样
So, how did it go?
大家都很开心
Everyone had a good time.
他们一直问我为什么我叔叔挖了地道
They kept asking me why my uncle built these tunnels.
你怎么说
What did you say?
我说你喜欢挖掘  还有点疯癫
I said that you like digging and you're a little crazy.
挺对的
That's fair enough.
我得跟你谈点事
I need to talk to you about something.
我希望你能用开放的心态来看
And I just want you to have an open mind about it.
我得去一趟墨西哥
I need to go to Mexico.
你为什么想去那里
Why would you want to do that?
因为我找到了我爸爸
Because I found my father.
我朋友吉赛尔  她住在墨西哥
My friend Gizelle, who lives there...
她原来住这里  你记得她吗
Well, she used to live here. Do you remember her?
我让她帮个忙  她找到了他
I asked her for a favor, and she found him.
他住在她附近的一个镇里
He lives in a town near hers.
约翰叔叔  我必须去
Uncle John, I have to do this.
我需要听他亲口说出来
I need to hear it from him.
我需要明白他为什么那么做
I need to understand why he would just do that.
因为他不是好人
Because he's not a good man.
-不可能那么简单  -就那么简单
- Can't be that simple. - It is.
约翰叔叔  我听过那些故事
Uncle John, I've heard the stories.
我知道你经历过很多
I know you've been through a lot.
我的世界与你的完全不同
But my world is a lot different from yours.
确实  你的更可怕
No, it's not. It's worse.
不是的
No, it's not.
人不会无缘无故做坏事
People don't just act bad for no reason.
一个男人不管有什么理由都不能抛弃家庭
There's no reason for a man to throw his family away.
能有个家庭就够幸运了
He's lucky he has one.
-你为什么这么生气  -因为你不知道这个世界多坏
- Why are you getting so mad? - Because you don't know how bad it is.
我知道人心能有多黑暗
I know how black a man's heart can be.
这世上没有好人  加布里埃尔
There's nothing good out there, Gabrielle.
也许他变了
Maybe he's changed.
那种男人不会变  只会变得更坏
Men like that don't change. It only gets worse.
你就变了
You changed.
我没变
I haven't changed.
我只是努力控制住自己  日日如此
I'm just trying to keep a lid on it, every day.
约翰叔叔  我需要你信任我
Uncle John, I need you to trust me.
我需要你知道我会做出正确的决定
I need you to know that I'm gonna make good decisions.
我控制不了外面的世界
I can't control what's out there.
你不可能永远保护我
You can't just protect me forever.
只要我还有一口气
As long as I'm around,
他就别想再伤害你
he's never gonna hurt you again.
没人能
No one is.
你说你做了你认为正确的事  十七岁就离开了
You said you did what you thought was right and left at 17,
没人阻止你
and nobody stopped you.
我希望他们阻止了
I wish they had.
加布里埃尔  你就像我女儿一样
Gabrielle, I care for you like a daughter.
我知道你想要答案
I know you want answers.
稍微等一等
Just wait a little while.
再长大一点
Grow up a little bit.
再多了解这世界一点
Know about the world a little bit.
你愿意为我这么做吗
Would you do that for me, please?
好吧
All right.
谢谢
Thanks.
我要睡了  晚安
I'm gonna go to bed. Good night.
晚安
Good night.
他从来都不希望你靠近那个人
我只想知道原因
I just wanna know why.
谁在乎原因
那男人就是行尸走肉  他没有心  没有灵魂
怎么了
What's going on?
她想去见她父亲
She wants to see her father.
加布里埃尔  我以为我们已经说好了
Gabrielle, I thought we had an understanding.
是啊  是啊  对不起
We did. We did. I'm sorry.
但我考虑了一晚上...
But I've been thinking about it all night, and...
我现在就想知道答案  不是以后
I just want answers now, not later.
你怎么找到他的
How did you find him?
吉赛尔帮了我
Gizelle helped me.
吉赛尔
Gizelle.
她还跟吉赛尔有联系
吉赛尔不是什么好女孩
她已经变了
不  她没变
她当初走了我可高兴了
她是想帮我
She's trying to help me.
他根本不会记得你
他从来就没有个当父亲的样子
这个人才更像你的父亲
That man is more your father.
照顾你  保护你
Watching over you, protecting you.
最近这十年  他就是你父亲
These last ten years, he was the father.
玛丽亚  别激动
Maria, go easy.
不激动  为什么
No. Why?
因为所以
Because.
他根本不配见到你
你妈得癌症快病死的时候  他一次都没去过医院
有一次圣诞节他用皮带抽你妈妈  约翰连拉带拽才把他拉开
够了
That's enough.
告诉她
Tell her.
我不希望你靠近那个人
我们不会让你去危险的地方
别说了
好吧
Okay.
你说得对  我不去了
You're right. I won't go.
我去安东尼娅家
I'm gonna go to Antonia's.
好的  抱歉
Okay. Sorry.
没事的  她还是个孩子
It's all right. She's a kid.
约翰叔叔
Uncle John!
刚才的事真对不起
Sorry about everything earlier!
没关系
That's okay!
好
Okay.
墨西哥
玛雅罗恩街
快过来
Come here!
瞧瞧你
Look at you.
你真美  姐妹儿
时间长了点  但没关系
你还是处女吗
别紧张  我开玩笑的
瞧你这一身尘土  肯定渴了
-要喝点什么吗  -不用  谢谢
- You want something to drink? - No, I'm okay.
我要喝
I do.
我就坐在这里
I'll just sit here.
你知道我能感觉到你在四处打量吧
You know, I can feel you looking around.
什么
What?
这房子很棒  对吧
It's a nice house, huh?
对  挺好的
Yeah, it's fine.
我还能感觉到你在打量我
I can feel you looking at me too.
没有
No.
没  你看起来很棒
No. You look great.
我知道我变了不少
I know I've changed.
姐妹  这里的生活不容易
Life down here, it ain't easy, my sister.
你得尽力而为
You do what you can.
我明白
Yeah, I get it.
我非常感激你帮我找我爸爸
I appreciate you so much for helping me find my dad.
并不容易  但没关系
I mean, it wasn't easy, but it's cool.
-我想给你个东西  -不不不
- Let me give you something... - No, no, no.
你当我是什么慈善对象吗
You think I'm some fucking charity case?
不  吉赛尔
No, Gizelle.
-我没有  -我开玩笑的
- I didn't... - I was kidding.
好吧
Okay.
我有那么一秒真差点信了
I actually believed you there for a second.
你知道我绝不会那样伤害你的感情
You know I would never hurt your feelings like that.
等我喝完这瓶  然后...
我们就去见你老爸吧
We'll go see your old man.
好
Okay.
来
Come on!
到了  172号
Here it is, 172.
去找你老爸吧  妹子
Go on. Get your daddy, girl.
2号公寓  找到了
Apartment number two. Okay.
你好
Hola.
曼纽尔在吗
你是谁
我只想跟他说几句话
你想干什么
你在跟谁说话呢
她是谁
我回头解释
我没有你的手机号码
我没想到你会来
I did not expect this.
实在是太久了
It's been a very long time.
我知道
I know.
你现在都是个大姑娘了  加布里埃尔
You're all grown up now, Gabriela.
你怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
不容易
It wasn't easy.
你一直很聪明
You always had a good head on your shoulders.
哪怕是小时候  你也总是学校里最优秀的
Even as a little girl, you always did good in school.
我得跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
你现在看起来跟你妈妈一模一样
Just now you looked just like your mother.
是吗
Really?
是的  非常像
Yes, very much.
你都能当她的双胞胎了
You could almost be her twin.
谢谢  我...我得问你一个问题
Thank you. Um, I need to... I need to ask you a question.
当然可以
Of course.
你当初为什么离开我们
Why did you leave us?
我只是想理解你为什么就那么走了
I'm just trying to understand why you would just go like that.
好吧
Okay.
因为有一天  我看着你和你妈妈
Because one day, I looked at your mother and you
我意识到你俩对我而言都没有任何意义了
and realized you both didn't mean anything to me anymore.
我知道这很难理解
I know it's hard to understand.
因为我浪费了太多时间
But I wasted time
跟你在一起
being with you...
还有她
and her.
然后她死了  留下我跟你一起
And she fucking dies and leaves me with you,
我从来就没想要你
who I never wanted.
还有问题吗
Any more questions?
你不用再回来了
You don't need to come back.
怎么了  妹子  发生了什么
Hey, what happened? Girl, what happened?
我应该听他的  他一直都是对的
I should've listened to him. He was right the whole time.
-我今晚得回家  -谁
- I got to get back home tonight. - Who?
去他的  你不能开车回家
Fuck that! You're not gonna drive home.
太晚了  你情绪又这么不好
It's too late and you're too upset.
我来帮你  但你得冷静下来
Yo, let me help you. You got to calm down, though.
我们得做点什么让你忘掉这些
We'll do something to get this out of your mind.
我来开车
I'll drive.
你好啊
Hi. How are you?
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
唐 米高
Don Miguel.
谢谢你的到来
Thank you for coming.
你想喝点什么吗?
Do you want something to drink?
- 我时间不多 - 那就直接谈生意吧
- I don't have much time. - Let's go straight to business.
我听说你想拓展业务
I heard you want to expand your business.
是的 公司需要成长
I want to grow.
与你合作 我就能成功 我们会是最佳拍档
With your help I can achieve that. We'd be partners.
我一直在寻找新的少女
I always look for new whores.
去年我已经输出了超过一万七千名女孩
I've exported more than 17 000 girls last year.
即使是丑的 也可以让我们盈利超过三十万
Even the ugliest ones, can make us more than 300 000.
唐 米高 你看起来很不错啊
Don Miguel, you look perfect!
走远点
Leave us.
我知道你喜欢我们的女孩 他们质量是最好的
I knew you would like our girls. They are of the best quality.
我听说你发了一批货往纽约
I heard you sent a shipment to New York.
走开 维达
Leave us, Victor.
我需要跟米高谈谈
I need to speak to Miguel.
那就在这里说啊 有什么问题吗?
So speak here. What's the problem?
雨果 谁管理那地方 你俩商量好以后 请通知我
Hugo, after you guys decide who runs the place, let me know.
请给我一分钟 唐 米高
Please give me a minute, Don Miguel.
维达
Victor.
你怎么回事?
What is wrong with you?
你知道什么是业务吗?
Do you know what's on the line?
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
我的工作就是 找到最好的妓女
I work my ass off, getting the best whores.
而谈生意时 我居然不能在场?
And I cannot be present when business is happening?
你这样让我很没面子
You make me look bad.
- 放松点 - 闭上你的嘴 蠢驴
- Go easy. - Shut your mouth.
这不是玩的时候 也不是玩的地方
This is not the time, nor place to play around.
业务上有很多钱要赚
There is a lot of money on the line.
你谈你的业务
You do your way,
我会尽我所能
and I'll do mine.
不好意思 失陪
Excuse me.
约翰  约翰
John! John!
-怎么了  -她根本没去安东尼娅家
- What's the matter? - She never went to Antonia's.
-她去了墨西哥  -什么
- She went to Mexico. - What?
吉赛尔打电话来了  加布里埃尔
Gizelle called. Gabriela went to
去见了她爸  一直没回来
see her father and never came back.
你有地址吗
Did you get an address?
还有她爸的地址
And her father's too.
这是怎么回事  约翰
What happened, John?
-我要报警吗  -警察不能越境
- Should I call the police? - Cops can't cross the border.
他们在那边什么也做不了
Down there, they don't do shit.
拜托了  约翰
Please, John.
把她带回我身边
我会找到她的
I'll find her.
我控制不了外面的世界
I can't control what's out there.
你不可能永远保护我
You can't just protect me forever.
事实是...
我喜欢狗
但如果它们敢逃跑
我就会生气
它就得受到惩罚
我能说什么呢  那会让我不爽
如果你们哪个小婊子想逃跑
尽管试试  跑吧
但我会找到你们
而且我会杀了你们
我发誓
我找加布里埃尔
I'm looking for Gabrielle.
她不在这里
She's not here.
那她在哪
Where is she?
我什么也不知道
I don't know anything.
这些破事都是因为你
All this shit is because of you.
我十年前就该拧断你的脖子
I should've broke your fucking neck ten years ago.
吉赛尔
Gizelle.
你是谁
你想怎样
我叫约翰  我们之前见过几次
My name is John. We've met a few times before.
-我找加布里埃尔  -她不在这里
- I'm looking for Gabrielle. - She's not here.
你知道她可能在哪吗
Do you know where she could be?
不知道  她找我帮忙找她父亲
I don't know. She wanted help finding her old man.
我只知道这个
That's all I know.
我能问几个问题吗  关于发生的事
You mind if I ask you a few questions about what happened?
可以  但我知道的并不多
Okay, but I don't know much.
进去说吧  如果你不介意的话
Inside, if you don't mind.
好吧
Okay.
她非常伤心
She was so sad.
他相当于让她滚蛋了  我只是想帮忙
He basically told her to fuck off, and I just wanted to help.
然后发生了什么
Then what happened?
发生了什么
What happened?
她大哭了一场  让我感觉很难过
She was crying a lot. And it made me feel bad.
我不想带她回到
I didn't want to bring her back to
这个破地方  因为太压抑了
this shithole because it's depressing.
我觉得带她出去
I thought it might be better if I took her out,
安抚她  让她清醒一下
calm her down, get her head clear,
或许喝点酒更好
maybe get some drinks.
然后我们到了一个地方  就走散了
And then we went to this place, and then we got separated.
-我不知道发生了什么  -怎么会
- And I don't know what happened! - How?
因为我喝多了  正常啊
Because I drank too much. It happens.
我和几个朋友聊天
I was talking to a couple of friends,
然后找她  就发现她不见了
and then I looked up and she wasn't there.
我到处都找过了
And I looked for her everywhere.
我以为她先走了
And I thought maybe she left.
我不知道  我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
她不辞而别
She left without saying goodbye?
是  我不知道  可能吧
Yeah, I don't know, maybe.
有人载我去的  我都记不清是谁
Somebody drove me there, and I don't even know who.
是的  我说了我喝多了
And, yeah, I said I was fucked up.
她和什么人说过话吗  男人
Was she talking to anyone, any guys?
什么
What?
她和什么男人说过话吗
Was she talking to any guys?
我也不知道  可能吧
I don't know, man! Maybe.
她肯定和几个男人说过话
She must've talked to a few guys.
你为什么问我这些废话  难道我在骗你吗
Why you asking me all this shit? You think I'm lying to you?
你打电话到我家
You called my house
说她一直没从她父亲家回来
and said she never came back from her father's.
是  我是想提醒你一下
Yeah, I was giving you a heads-up.
-或是想摆脱责任  -去你的...
- Or covering your ass. - Man, fuck you...
这是哪来的
Where did you get this?
她送我的
She gave it to me, man.
这是她母亲的
It was her mother's.
她绝对不可能送给你
She'd never give it to you.
你把她卖了
You sold her out.
她是你的朋友
She was your friend.
去你的  滚出我家
Fuck you! Get out of my place!
看着我
Look at me.
你要带我去那家夜店
You're gonna take me to that club,
告诉我她跟谁说过话
and you're gonna show me who she was with.
否则我就把你千刀万剐
Or I'm gonna hurt you real bad.
走吧
Let's go.
下车
Get out.
乡村夜店
该死  我不能进去
Shit, man. I can't go in there.
他们认识我  我还要在这里混呢
People know me. I got to live down here.
你要进去  把他们指出来
You're gonna go inside and you're gonna point them out.
如果你有别的举动
If you do anything else,
我保证会在他们
then I promise I'll put a bullet
对我动手之前一枪崩了你
in your head before they can get me.
走
Move.
我没变  我只是努力控制住自己
I haven't changed. I'm just trying to keep a lid on it.
我的世界与你的完全不同
My world is a lot different from yours.
因为你不知道这个世界多坏
Because you don't know how bad it is.
我知道人心能有多黑暗
I know how black a man's heart can be.
就是他  沙发上的那个
That's the guy, man. On the couch.
-没我事了吧  -滚蛋
- We're cool, right? - Fuck off.
滚出去吧
Get out of here.
我马上回来
I'll be back.
滚
她在哪
我不认识这个贱人
好吧
Okay.
告诉我她在哪  否则我就掰断它
Start telling me where she is, or I'll break it off.
好的  好的
Okay. Okay.
姑娘们  老实点
没日没夜地接客就好
甭管是四十个还是五十个男人
没有命令不许停下来
老实点
停车
哪所房子
顶层那所
亮着灯的
开始吧 他们都是你们的了 玩得开心点
Let's go! They are all yours! Have fun!
刀不错啊
你来这做什么
你迷路了吗  老头
不说话吗
那我用这把刀把你的嘴划开如何
维多
Vito.
亚利桑那州
Arizona.
怎么
你们那的妓女不够使了吗
我认识这个妞
这婊子在我们这儿
她是你的什么人
够了
把他扶起来
放她走
Let her go.
什么
What?
放她...
Let her...
-放她走  -放她走
- Let her go. - Let her go.
把他扔到酸里...
"约翰·兰博"
"John Rambo."
胡安尼托·兰博
Juanito Rambo.
知道吗  胡安尼托
Wanna know something, Juanito?
我和我的客户们根本不在乎这些女孩
These girls mean nothing to me or my customers.
在我的世界里  她们连人都算不上
In my world, they're nothing. They're not people.
她们只是...她们只是物品
They're just... They're just things.
对我们这样的男人来说她们毫无价值
They have no worth to men like us.
所以我本来不会注意到这个
So I would have not paid attention to this...
注意到她
to her.
但现在不一样了
But now I will.
因为你来这里对她太不利了  混蛋
Because you coming here has made it very bad for her, cabrón.
我们原本打算训练她  利用她  卖了她
We would've just trained her, used her and sold her.
但现在我们要拿她杀鸡儆猴了
But now we're gonna make an example of her.
我要放你一条生路
I'm gonna let you live.
你他妈说什么呢
别插嘴  维克多  操
你余生会每天都想着
You're gonna think about this every fucking day
这件事了
of your fucking life.
直到你再也无法思考的那天  胡安尼托
Until you can't think anymore, Juanito.
在他和他的小婊子脸上留下你的记号
深一点
起来
Get up.
我来帮你  能站起来吗
Let me help you. Can you stand?
好了  你得站起来  他们会回来的
Okay, you have to get up. They will come back.
放她走
Let her go.
你在开玩笑吗?
You think I'm stupid?
没人跟你开玩笑
No, I don't think that.
你当然有 我想马上杀了他 但你却跟他玩
I wanted to kill him straight away and you didn't let me.
你简直都快成了爱玩的大男孩
You embarassed me there.
你想要什么?
What do you want?
我想他死
Give me his girl.
- 这是门生意 - 我知道 但我还是想杀了他
- This is business. - I know, but now it's personal.
好吧
Alright.
不  不  不
No, no, no!
亚利桑那州驾驶证
约翰·兰博
这家伙是谁
你们从哪拿到的
不  不  不
No, no, no.
他是谁
现在都不重要了
他正躺在外面的大街上
脸上留下了我的记号
不  不  不
No, no, no.
如果他静养  应该可以愈合
他有严重的脑震荡  应该送往医院
我知道
好的
因为脑震荡  他对噪声和光线都很敏感
过几天应该就能好起来
卡门  你知道我关心你  但这件事太疯狂了
别担心
你醒了
You're up.
是的
Yeah.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
你是谁
Who are you?
卡门·戴尔加多
Carmen Delgado.
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
约翰
John.
对了  你的车在车库里
Your truck is in the garage, by the way.
我是怎么到这来的
How did I get here?
我带你来的
I brought you here.
你都不认识我
You don't even know me.
我必须要认识你吗
Why do I have to know you?
你遇上了麻烦
You were in trouble.
换做其他人我也会这么做
I don't know, I would do it for anyone.
你为什么会去那里
Why were you even there?
我是一名独立记者
I'm an independent journalist.
我当时在跟踪瘦子
I was following El Flaco...
一个贩卖毒品和妇女的皮条客
a pimp who drugs and sells girls.
我当时看到你在夜店里观察他
I saw you in the club, watching him.
我看到你对他做了什么
I saw what you did to him.
我来这里多久了
How long have I been here?
-四天  -四天
- Four days. - Four days?
天啊
Christ.
你得告诉我
You got to tell me...
带走她的那些人在哪
Where are the men that took her?
他们带走的是谁  你女儿
Who did they take? Your daughter?
对  她在哪
Yeah. Where is she?
他们是谁
Who are they?
维克多·马丁内斯         雨果·马丁内斯
马丁内斯兄弟
The Martínez brothers.
他们抢走了我妹妹
They took my sister.
三年前她被发现吸毒过量而死
They found her dead from an overdose three years ago.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
你要告诉我你认为他们在哪
You just got to tell me where you think they are.
不  这样不行的
No, it doesn't work this way.
他们人太多
There's too many of them.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy or what?
我没想这些
I'm not thinking about that.
我脑子里全是...
All I can think about is...
她会有多害怕
how scared she must be,
她在经历什么
what she's going through,
还有你妹妹经历了什么
and what your sister went through.
请你帮帮我
Just help me, please.
没有你我无法成功
I can't do it without you.
-好  -谢谢你
- Okay. - Thank you.
谢谢
Thanks.
你想要什么
姑娘
有年轻的吗
走
Go!
我不能  我不能
离开这里
我不能  他们会杀了我的
走  快走
Go! Come on!
该死的
God damn it!
不  不  不
No! No! No! No!
出去
Get out!
-加布里埃尔  过来  -不
- Gabrielle. Come here. - No!
-不  加布里埃尔  加布里埃尔  -不
- No, Gabrielle! Gabrielle. - No!
我是约翰
It's John. It's John.
我是约翰叔叔
It's Uncle John.
没事的  没事的
It's all right. It's all right.
我是你叔叔  你叔叔
It's your uncle. It's your uncle.
好了  我们回家
Okay. We're going home.
我带你回家  你现在安全了
You're going home. You're safe now.
没人看到什么吗
我说了让你杀了那个混蛋
够了  维托
是他干的
只有那个老混蛋会为了一个破相的婊子回来
我们会找到他然后杀了他
不不不
no,no,no.
我才不在乎他
这是你惹的乱子
你到底想怎样
下次照我说的做  兄弟
我们走
回去干活
你回来了
You came back.
我会带你回去  带你回家
We're gonna get you back, get you back home.
-对不起  -不
- I'm sorry. - No.
你没做错什么  什么都没做错
You didn't do anything. You didn't do anything at all.
我们回家  一切都会好的
We're gonna go home, and everything's gonna be good.
会没事的
It's gonna be all right.
好
Okay.
我帮你拿回了这个
I got this back for you.
加布里埃尔  你不能闭上眼睛
Gabrielle, I need you to keep your eyes open.
别闭眼
Keep your eyes open.
我们聊点什么
Let's talk about something.
我记得你骑马骑得很好
I remember you were a great rider.
每次活动  每次比赛
Every event you were in, every competition,
你都能赢
you'd win everything.
我记得你那时才十一岁
I remember you were just about 11 years old.
你一天赢了五场  真的很了不起
You won five events in one day. That's really something.
加布里埃尔  别闭眼
Gabrielle, stay with me.
你能行的  我们很快就到家了
You can do it. We're gonna be home soon.
我会照顾好你
I'll take care of you.
你还有漫长的人生
You got so much life left.
你还有许多要做的事
You got so many things you got to do.
许多事
So many things.
很久之前我回家时  你那么小
When I came home a long time ago, you were so young.
加布里埃尔  你那么小
Gabrielle, you were so young.
我很迷茫  我迷失了自我
I was lost. I was a lost man.
然后我见到了你
And then I met you.
我看到了我以为再也看不到的东西
And I saw something that I didn't think I'd ever see anymore:
这世上的美好  纯真
Good in this world. Some innocence.
我有了一个从不敢奢望的家
And I had a family that I never thought I'd ever have.
抚养你长大  是我这辈子最好的事
And raising you, it was the best thing that ever happened to me.
为此我谢谢你  谢谢你
And I thank you for that. Thank you.
你就像...
You're like the...
加布里埃尔  加布里埃尔
Gabrielle? Gabrielle.
加布里埃尔  不  不
Gabrielle. No, no.
别这样
Don't do it.
加布里埃尔
Gabrielle?
天啊
Oh, God.
对不起
I'm sorry.
为什么不是我
Why not me?
美国边界  禁止穿越
等等
Wait!
我想她
我希望你住在你妹妹家
I want you to stay at your sister's.
这里没什么让你留恋的了  我也没有
There's nothing for you here, nothing for me here.
你要去哪
Where will you go?
我四处漂泊
I'm just gonna move around.
一如往常
Like always.
我还会再见到你吗
Will I see you again?
会的
Sure.
我会想念这里
I will miss this.
我会哀痛一生
我感觉
我的心被挖出来了
是的
Yeah.
一路顺风
Travel safe.
你想要什么
What do you want?
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
进来
Come in.
如果有人看到你  我们两个都会死
If someone sees you, we both will die.
回来这里太危险了
Coming back here is so dangerous.
你找到她了吗
Did you find her?
她死了
She's dead.
我...
I'm...
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
真的  我明白你的感觉
I really am. I know how you feel.
但回来真的很危险
But coming back was dangerous.
你为什么来
Why are you here?
我想找到那个瘦子
I wanna find the thin one.
-不  -伤她那个人
- No. - The one that cut her.
-不  -伤我那个人
- No. - The one that cut me.
我不会再帮你
I will not help you again.
你必须帮我
You have to.
为什么
Why do I have to?
这能改变什么  什么也改变不了
What will it change? Nothing.
我们悲痛然后继续生活
We grieve and move on.
你做到了吗
And you've done that?
我每天都会想她
I mean, I think of her every day.
该死的每一天
Every fucking day.
但我们必须向前看
But we have to move on.
如果不能呢
What if you can't move on?
-如果完全不能呢  -可你必须那么做
- What if you can't move on at all? - But you have to.
我们别无选择  过去的已经过去了
We have no choice. What's done is done.
为什么过去了
Why is it done?
怎么可能过去
How is it ever done?
我看到她那张纯真的脸
When I look at something so innocent...
永远地失去了生命
and I see that face never have life in it again,
怎么可能过去
how is it ever done?
我要复仇
I want revenge.
我要让他们知道死期到了
I want them to know that death is coming...
他们做什么都无济于事
and there's nothing they can do to stop it.
我要让他们感受到我们的悲痛
I want them to feel our grief...
并且知道那是他们人生最后的感觉
and know that's the last thing they will ever feel.
我知道你也想这样
And I know you want it too.
去吧
Go!
镁片
警惕点  五个去畜棚  其余跟着我
抓住他  这个外国佬不算什么
Get him! This old gringo is nothing!
查理  去看看  其余人跟我来
收录机
正面向敌
这边
Here!
他们都死了
They're all dead.
所有人
All of them.
我本可以杀你十次
I could've killed you ten times.
但我想把你留到最后
But I wanted you last.
你去死
Fuck you.
不  你去死  你死定了
No, fuck you, dead man.
我想要你在被我剖胸挖心时
I want you to feel my rage, my hate,
感受我的愤怒  我的仇恨
when I reach into your chest and rip out your heart!
就像你对我做的那样
Like you did mine.
你去死
还有你那婊子
你想活吗
You want to live?
跟着灯光
Follow the lights.
就是这种感觉
This is what it feels like.
我一直活在死亡的世界
I've lived in a world of death.
我曾尝试回家
I tried to come home,
但从未真正回到家
but I never really arrived.
我的一部分精神和灵魂
A part of my mind and soul...
在途中迷失了
got lost along the way.
但我的心仍在这里
But my heart was still here,
我出生的地方
where I was born.
我会一直守护到死的地方
Where I would defend to the end...
我仅有的家人
the only family I've ever known.
我仅有的家
The only home I've ever known.
我爱的人现在都已逝去
All the ones I've loved are now ghosts.
但我会拼命
But I will fight...
让他们的记忆长存
to keep their memories alive...
直到永远
forever.
第一滴血5
最后的血